What is the difference between a free
content creation setup, a $1,000 content
creation setup,
and a 10,000 US dollar content creation
setup?
If you are a small business
or a personal brand and you
are not putting out
content, you are already falling behind.
But don't worry,
because in this video I'm going to talk
you through how to produce
and record amazing content depending on
your budget.
Right now, this is shot on iPhone.
Everyone has an iPhone.
Some people have Androids, and look,
if you were bullied at school,
cool. If you've got the 'tism, fine,
but let's all just agree that
video content looks better on iPhone.
And if you are someone with an Android,
maybe skip this part of the video and go
straight to the bit where we look at cheap
and affordable technology that you can
get to produce good-looking,
banging videos.
When it comes to shooting on iPhone,
the most important thing, natural light.
So whoever is filming you or your tripod,
you just move them to a
position where you have the light in front
of you.
Doesn't matter what your backdrop
is behind, don't care how messy
or cluttery it
is, face the light.
You'll also notice I'm having to talk
quite loud so that
the audio within the iPhone picks me up.
For beginners and novices,
it's completely fine.
Let's just remember,
if you're making content for Instagram,
Facebook, TikTok, you
will need to turn the phone
and shoot in portrait. But
if you're doing YouTube,
you would turn it back around
and shoot in landscape. Get a tripod.
Try and keep the camera at eye level,
because if the camera is beneath you, it
quite literally looks like you're talking
down to people.
And if the camera's too high,
it looks like you're a dwarf.
Did I say dwarf?
Is that the word? Midget? Dwarf?
Yeah.
Which one's politically correct?
Dwarf is fine.
Fine. What are they going to do?
The iPhone is completely fine up until the
point you can move away from it.
But before we get into big,
complicated cameras
and lenses that look really expensive,
let's appreciate you can do a lot with an
iPhone.
If we look at Matt Armstrong's Mark II
channel, the entire thing is filmed
with an iPhone. Yeah, sure,
the audio doesn't really do the trick now
and then, but
it goes to show that using an iPhone,
you can still produce millions of views
and
attract audiences and millions of people.
But imagine there was a world
that between expensive cameras
and cheap iPhones,
there was a piece of technology
that we could use
that would help us put out more
content without having to understand what
F-stop, exposure, aperture,
or any other of that complex stuff is.
Introducing the DJI Pocket Osmo 3.
There's a YouTube channel online by a guy
called Spanion who just uses
this and he gets millions of views.
Now,
one of the best features of the DJI Pocket
Osmo is that, let's say
yesterday, for whatever reason,
Declan messed up filming with it,
I can just pick
it up today and use it. And the thing is,
I don't need a videographer to hold
anything stable. I can just do it myself.
And again, let's say I
was doing a video on the benefits of using
an infrared sauna.
I'm not sure you're supposed to get in
them with your clothes
on. And then again,
let's just say you wanted to talk about
something, you could do
that. Then if the audio quality,
for whatever reason, wasn't as good,
you could then put on your microphone
here.
Again,
these are also great for using inside your
car.
Although I will say that
if you're going to film inside your car,
it has to be car
content. Because any of you that
are just trying to get a shortcut,
I know what it
is. You're like, "Oh,
I'm driving to the gym,
so I'm just going to film and chat
about something." You can end up getting
something, maybe even sitting it on a
gimbal here. You drive along,
everything sounds amazing.
You're not supposed to hold these
while you drive, but you get the drift.
Suddenly, if you were to try
and get a passenger sat here with a 10K
camera, there
probably wouldn't be enough room.
And you'll even notice
that not only does the YouTube channel
Spanion, which I'll
show you a clip of now,
Spanion managed to grow his channel to
well over a
million followers
and gets absolutely insane views using a
DJI Pocket Osmo.
But even the likes of Carwow use one of
these when doing car reviews or
whatever. Very versatile bit of kit,
very easy to use.
And I think also it's worth saying,
sometimes it's nice to have a separate
device.
So for instance, my phone over here,
my phone's what I use for personal stuff.
It's nice sometimes
that you've got a device,
something you put in front of you and
you're like, "Do you know what?
This thing here is for content.
This thing here is what I'm going to build
my business on.
This thing here is what I'm going to grow
my brand on.
This thing here,
I'm going to talk to every day
and make content.
This thing here is going to be the weapon
that I use so that eventually I
can have cameras and a setup
that looks like that." This
is a stepping stone to a
full-on production,
but for the time being,
it just makes everything so much
easier. DJI Pocket Osmo, $1,000.
Absolute incredible bit of
kit. Big fan of it. Still use it now
and then.
Everyone should probably get one,
unless you can afford one of them.
Which probably leads me onto the $10,000
setup.
Ladies and gentlemen, this
is a $10,000 setup.
As you can see,
Rembrandt light to the side,
microphone out of shot,
50-millimeter lens on an FX3.
It's looking pretty good.
I think two things, if I'm honest.
Firstly, it is so much
better to have the correct message on the
wrong camera than the wrong message on
the right camera.
You can have the best-looking setup in the
world, but if you're
chatting absolute gas, there's no point.
But then also at the same time,
people like for you to not only respect
their
time with editing, retention speed,
but people at the same time also like you
to respect them.
Don't make a video longer than it needs to
be.
Respect their time
and put on a production for them.
Every one of you should be making the best
content possible at the highest
production possible to you.
And whatever setup you're currently using,
just keep
maxing it out until you can upgrade it to
the next level.
I put together a short content creation
course. It's $99.
There's going to be a link to it in the
description.
And if you're not interested in paying me,
then there's also 30 tips over the next
30 days that you can access completely for
free that are going to help you put out
better content and level up your business
in general.
So if you're interested in those,
they're in the link below.